Hello everyone and welcome back.
欢迎回来
So, in this notebook and series of videos,
在此 notebook 和下面的视频中
I'm going to be showing you a more powerful way to build neural networks and PyTorch.
我将介绍在 PyTorch 中构建神经网络的另一种方式
So, in the last notebook, you saw how you can calculate the output for
在上个 notebook 中 我介绍了
network using tensors and matrix multiplication.
如何使用张量和矩阵乘法计算网络的输出
But PyTorch has this nice module, nn,
PyTorch 有一个很强大的模块 叫做 nn
that has a lot of my classes and methods and
其中包含大量类 方法和函数
functions that allow us to build large neural networks in a very efficient way.
使我们能够非常高效地构建大型神经网络
So, to show you how this works,
为了演示它的功能
we're going to be using a dataset called MNIST.
我们将使用数据库 MNIST
So, MNIST it's a whole bunch of grayscale handwritten digits.
MNIST 包含了很多灰阶手写数字图像
So ,0, 1, 2, 3,
0 1 2 3 4
4 and so on through nine.
一直到 9
Each of these images is 28 by 28 pixels and the goal is
每个图像都是 28 x 28 像素
to actually identify what the number is in these images.
我们的目标是识别图像中的数字
So, that dataset consists of each of these images and
这个数据库由这些图像组成
it's labeled with the digit that is in that image.
并且用图像中的数字加以标注
So, ones are labeled one,
1 标注为 1
twos are labeled two and so on.
2 标注为 2
So, what we can do is we can actually show
我们可以向网络提供
our network and image and the correct label and
这些图像和正确的标签
then it learns how to actually determine what the number and the image is.
网络将学习判断图像中的数字是多少
This dataset is available through the torchvision package.
我们可以通过 torchvision 软件包获取该数据库
So, this is a package that sits alongside PyTorch,
torchvision 是 PyTorch 配套的软件包
that provides a lot of nice utilities like
它能提供很多实用工具 例如数据库和模型
datasets and models for doing computer vision problems.
有助于我们解决计算机视觉问题
We can run this cell to download and load the MNIST dataset.
我们可以运行此单元格并下载和加载 MNIST 数据库
What it does is it gives us back an object which I'm calling trainloader.
它将返回一个对象 我称之为 trainloader
So, with this trainloader we can turn into an iterator with iter and then
使用 iter 将 trainloader 变成迭代器
this will allow us to start getting good at
从而从中获取数据
it or we can actually just use this in a loop,
或者在 for 循环里使用它
in a for loop and so we can get our images and labels out
从这个生成器里获取图像
of this generator with four image,
代码是
comma label and trainloader.
for image, label in trainloader
One thing to notice is that when I created the trainloader,
要注意的一点是 当我创建 trainloader 时
I set the batch size to 64.
我将批次大小设成了 64
So, what that means and every time we get a set of images and labels out,
这样的话 每次我们都会
we're actually getting 64 images out from our data loader.
从数据加载器里获得 64 个图像和标签
So, then if you look at the shape and the size of these images,
查看这些图像的形状和大小后
we'll see that they are 64 by one by 28 by 28.
会发现有 64 个图像 大小是1x28x28
So, 64 images and then one color channels so it's grayscale,
因此有一个颜色通道 表明是灰阶图像
and then it's 28 by 28 pixels is the shape of these images and so we can see that here.
图像形状是 28 x 28 像素
Then our labels have a shape of 64 so it's just a vector that's 64 elements which with
标签的形状是 64 它是一个向量 包含 64 个元素
a label for each of our images and we can see what
每个图像对应一个标签
one of these images looks like this is a nice number four.
这是数字 4 的图像
So, we're going to do here is build
我们将使用
a multi-layer neural network using the methods that we saw before.
之前学习的方法构建多层神经网络
By that I mean you're going to initialize some weight matrices and
初始化权重矩阵和偏差向量
some bias vectors and use those to calculate the output of this multi-layer network.
并使用它们计算这个多层网络的输出
Specifically, we want to build this network with 784 input units,
具体而言 我们要构建的网络有 784 个输入单元
256 hidden units, and 10 output units.
256 个隐藏单元和 10 个输出单元
So, 10 output units,
10 个输出单元是指
one for each of our classes.
每个类别对应一个单元
So, the 784 input units,
784 个输入单元的原因是
this comes from the fact that with this type of network is
这种网络
called a fully connected network or a dense network.
称为完全连接网络或密集网络
We want to think of our inputs as just one vector.
输入可以看做是一个向量
So, our images are actually this 28 by 28 image,
图像是 28 x 28
but we want to put a vector into our network and so what we need to do is
但是我们要向网络里输入一个向量
actually convert this 28 by 28 image into a vector and so,
因此我们需要将这个 28 x 28 图像转换成向量
784 is 28 times 28.
28 x 28 = 784
When we actually take this 28 by 28 image and flatten it into
当我们将这个 28 x 28 图像扁平化为向量时
a vector then it's going to be 784 elements long.
向量的长度将是 784 个元素
So, now what we need to do is take each of our batches
我们需要转换每批数据
which is 64 by one by 28 by 28 and then
即将 64 x 1 x 28 x 28
convert it into a shape that is to another tensor which shapes 64 by 784.
转换为另一个张量 形状为 64 x 784
This is going to be the tensor that's the input to our network.
这就是将要输入到网络中的张量
So, go and give this a shot.
来吧 试试这个练习
So again, build the networks 784 input units,
创建一个网络 有 784 个输入单元
256 hidden units and 10 output units and you're going to be
256 个隐藏单元和 10 个输出单元
generating your own random initial weight and bias matrices. Cheers.
你要自己随机生成初始权重和偏差矩阵加油！